Baby ?
( CREAKS IN DISTANCE )
( CREAKING )
( GASPS ) Oh , you scared me .
( LAUGHS ) Sorry .
Didn 't mean to .
You were outside ?
- Why didn 't you wake me ? - I wanted to be alone .
I mean , I needed to clear my head
and get the ideas flowing .
And did they ?
No .
They will .
Don 't worry .
It 'll come .
- I must stink . - I like it .
I better shower .
( RUMBLING )
( PULSATING )
( GASPS SOFTLY )
( EXHALES )
HIM : Hey .
- Can I grab these ? - I got it .
( HIM CLEARS THROAT )
( LIQUID POURING )
Ooh .
Perfect .
You didn 't need to do all of this .
I wanted to .
You 've been working so hard .
Yeah . Right .
( HIM MUMBLING )
( SIGHS )
( KNOCK ON DOOR )
Wait here .
( INDISTINCT CONVERSATION )
( HIM LAUGHS )
HIM : No , no , no . It 's fine . It 's fine .
- Come in . Please . - Thanks . Thanks .
Oh . Hello .
- Hello . - ( DOOR CLOSES )
So this gentleman here just started working
at the hospital , and he thought we were ...
- What do you do there ? - I 'm an orthopedic surgeon .
HIM : Really ?
MAN : But mostly now I do research and teach .
Research .
Yes . I know , it 's a bit boring .
( LAUGHS ) It 's not boring at all .
Sit for a second . Can we get you anything to drink ?
No . That isn 't ... That 's fine .
- Some tea ? - Hmm ?
- Some tea ? - No , no , no , no , no .
Uh , I don 't ...
Uh ...
( STUTTERS ) I don 't want to be a bother .
But you must .
A guest and a doctor ? I mean , who knows ?
I might trip down the stairs one day .
( LAUGHS ) Let 's hope not !
- I 'll go make some . - Thank you .
HIM : This way please .
Sorry for the mess .
We 're moving in after months of construction .
MAN : It 's an incredible place .
HIM : My wife loves having company .
- MAN : Your wife ? - Yes .
I thought it was your daughter .
( HIM LAUGHS )
- HIM : Sit down . - Thank you very much .
( EXHALES )
( GROANS )
( GASPS )
HIM : You all right ?
Fine .
( GASPING )
( BREATHES DEEPLY )
( SIGHS )
( KETTLE WHISTLING )
MAN : Then there 's this one case ,
This was an opera singer , late 20s .
Her femurs were rotated so far inward
that she couldn 't spread her knees more than a foot apart .
HIM : Ooh , really ?
- Thank you . - MOTHER : You 've upgraded .
- Where 'd that come from ? - I always carry a supply .
I never tasted something like this .
It 's hard to come by . I had to share .
Won 't you join ?
Mmm . She 's not much of a drinker .
I drink .
Here , let me put a little in your tea .
I 'm fine with tea , thank you .
( HIM CHUCKLES )
The good doctor here is about to publish a major paper .
" About " is generous .
I still have reams of research to write up .
And he 's moved here to finish it .
And ... And what brings you to us ?
Well , they told me I could find a room here .
He thought we were a bed and breakfast .
( CHUCKLES )
We always talk about
how this place is too big for the two of us .
Well , I really should be going
if I 'm going to find another ...
Nonsense . No , no . No , it 's late . Stay the night .
MAN : No , I couldn 't , no .
Please . We 'd enjoy the company , right ?
Yes , of course .
- Are you sure ? - Positive .
Well , then I 'll just grab the rest of my stuff .
That 's incredibly kind and generous .
I just left it on the ... ( COUGHING )
- You all right ? - I 'm fine .
- ( CONTINUES COUGHING ) - HIM : You sure ?
MAN : Yeah . It just went down the wrong tube .
Thanks .
We don 't know him .
He 's a doctor .
He 's a stranger .
We 're just gonna let him sleep in our house ?
You want me to ask him to leave ?
- Is that all ? - That 's everything .
Um , we don 't smoke .
That 's smart .
In the house , I mean .
Sorry .
I 'll go get you some linens .
- I 'll show you to your room . - MAN : Thank you .
HIM : Once again , sorry for the mess .
MAN : No , please . I really appreciate this .
( SOFT RUMBLE )
- ( LOUD THUD ) - ( GASPS )
( SIGHS )
( INDISTINCT CONVERSATION )
Oh , and this ! I love this .
How come you have so many copies ?
Well , I wrote it .
Oh , my .
- That 's you ? - Mmm-hmm .
- I 'm a huge fan . - You 've read it ?
MAN : I 've read it many , many times .
Your words have changed my life .
Oh , I 'm sorry . You must ...
You must hear that all the time .
Not really , no .
MAN : And that .
What is that ?
HIM : Careful .
This is very , very delicate .
It was a gift .
MAN : A very special gift .
Is it from you ?
No .
When I was younger , I lost everything in a fire .
MAN : Oh , I 'm sorry .
It 's hard to imagine what that means .
Losing everything .
Your memories , your work , even your dirty toothbrush .
I didn 't know if I could ever create again
until I found this in the ashes .
Isn 't that remarkable ?
MAN : Can I just ...
It gave me the strength to start again .
And then I met her .
You .
And she breathed life back into every room .
She redid all of it .
Every last detail .
- By yourself ? - Mmm-hmm .
Wow .
So you 're not just a pretty face .
( COUGHING )
I just came up to say I 'm gonna get ready for bed .
( CONTINUES COUGHING ) I 'm sorry . I didn 't ...
You okay ? Want some water ?
Are you all right ?
I 'll be up soon .
Sure you don 't want some water ?
Just a little bit .
Here you go .
Sit down .
( MAN RETCHING )
HIM : You just drank too much .
( RETCHING AND COUGHING )
You 're okay . It 's okay .
Is everything all right ?
He drank too much . He 'll be fine .
- What is ... - Give him some privacy .
Okay , get it up .
Just get it all up .
( MAN CONTINUES RETCHING )
( CLATTERS )
( GROANS SOFTLY )
( CREAKING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( TAP RUNNING )
( GASPING )
( EXHALES )
( SIZZLING )
( HIM EXHALES )
- HIM : Good morning . - Morning .
Smells great .
What happened last night ?
I couldn 't sleep . I got so excited .
From what ?
His stories . I love the man 's mind .
It is so inspiring , speaking to someone who really appreciates the work .
I love your work .
Of course you do . I know that .
So is he better ?
HIM : Pardon ?
MOTHER : Is he feeling better ?
( URINATING )
- Is he all right ? - Fine , fine . One sec .
( GASPS )
Oh , sorry . Just need a light .
Don 't worry about it . I 'll take it outside .
- Morning . - Good morning .
How are you feeling ?
Wonderful .
You 're all better ?
Better ?
( TOILET FLUSHING )
- HIM : Morning ! - MAN : Morning !
- How did you sleep ? - Like a baby .
( HIM CHUCKLING )
Really vivid dreams . Must be the air .
Well , I 'm confused .
( DOORBELL RINGS )
- Who 's that ? - I 'll get it .
No , don 't . I 'll get it .
MAN : Expecting guests ?
HIM : We don 't really get visitors .
MAN : That would drive me crazy .
HIM : Tell me about it .
- Hello . - Hello .
- Can I help you ? - Ah , you made it !
My better half .
WOMAN : Get rid of that thing , won 't you ? MAN : I 'm not inhaling .
( BOTH MOANING )
Nice to meet you .
- Oh , the pleasure is mine . - Well , come in .
I didn 't realise you were married .
Really ?
( SMOKE ALARM BEEPING )
Breakfast !
HIM : I 'll grab her suitcase . WOMAN : Oh .
( SIZZLING )
( GROANS )
Oh , it 's burning .
- No , don 't ! - Oh !
- Oh , sorry . - I got it !
MAN : Sit down . HIM : I 'll get the windows .
- ( WOMAN GROANS ) - MAN : Let me look at it .
- Are you all right ? - I think so .
You 're okay . Ice .
Ice !
- ( ALARM CONTINUES BEEPING ) - WOMAN : So stupid .
MAN : It 's not bad . It 's fine . You 're fine .
Oh .
- MAN : Thank you . - I 'm really so sorry .
WOMAN : Oh , don 't worry about it .
It 's very nice to meet you .
- Very nice to meet ... You . - ( ALARM STOPS )
( INDISTINCT CHATTER )
( LAUGHTER )
WOMAN : Oh , please !
MAN : I 'd given up on romance .
I was getting used to being alone .
Oh , thank you .
- But then ... - WOMAN : Yummy .
... it just happened for us .
I saw her , and I knew she was the woman
I wanted to spend the rest of my life with .
- Hmm . Love at first sight . - WOMAN : Same here .
MAN : Yeah , right .
What ? How could I resist this face ?
You believe me , right ?
HIM : Come . Sit already .
- So you never had a doubt ? - WOMAN : That 's true .
- MAN : Oh , yeah . Come on . - What ?
- Didn 't you have any doubts ? - No ! Not a one .
You guys understand that kind of connection , right ?
You must .
I mean , you 're both so different .
It must have been what pulled you together .
You 're so beautiful . Come here .
( BOTH MOANING )
And then the kids came and screwed it all up .
- You have kids ? - MAN : Two .
- Boys . - HIM : Beautiful .
Here . This is my eldest .
HIM : Let me see .
MAN : And then her baby . WOMAN : Oh , shut up .
- Oh , amazing eyes . - MOTHER : Mmm .
And you two ?
You have kids ?
Not yet . But we want them .
WOMAN : Well , what are you waiting for ?
Why not finish breakfast and get to it ?
Well , I want to finish the house ,
and he 's working on a new piece .
Oh , so you 're writing again ?
- Yeah . - WOMAN : Oh .
MAN : That 's wonderful . WOMAN : Finally , right ?
Yes .
Oh , no . We 're in the way .
That 's the last thing in the world ...
HIM : No , no , not at all . No , no .
You 're more than welcome to stay here as long as you want .
That 's very kind of you .
WOMAN : No , we couldn 't impose .
Honey , they 've got plenty of room .
Speaking of kids , do you have a phone ?
I can 't get a signal .
That 's how we like it .
MAN : You don 't have to call him every day .
There 's one in the kitchen . I can show you .
No , it 's all right .
( SIGHS ) Can we just relax for the weekend ?
WOMAN : No , honey , I just want to let him know we 're okay .
Just a quick call .
What 's wrong ?
Why would you do that without asking me ?
- Do what ? - Invite them to stay .
I didn 't think it was a big deal .
- It 's strange . - What ?
Did you know he had a wife ?
What about your writing ?
I was actually enjoying not thinking about it .
But now that I am thinking about it ,
I should go and do something about it .
Hey . Hey .
I really should work .
( INDISTINCT CHATTER )
WOMAN : Lemonade !
Oops . Oh !
Careful .
Thought you might like some .
Yes , thank you .
Secret family recipe .
Which part ? The lemons ?
- How 's your hand ? - Mmm .
- Still stinging . - I 'm sorry .
It 's not like it was your fault .
You don 't have any painkillers , do you ?
Are you telling me the truth ?
I really don 't have any . I 'm sorry .
Okay .
You 're not thirsty ?
Right .
( GROANS SOFTLY )
Now I get it .
- It 's strong . - I 'm on my second .
I can 't believe you did all this work yourself .
- Why not ? - It 's a lot .
Well , we spend all our time here .
I want to make it paradise .
And I love the work .
And it 's exquisite .
Thank you .
Would you take me on a tour ?
Sure .
I want to thank you for your hospitality .
Your husband has been so generous .
You 're welcome .
Well , where to begin ?
Well , this was the hardest part .
There was so much damage . The treads were gone ,
the railing , even the skylight .
So I had to get a lot of new material ,
but I tried to save as much ...
Isn 't it a lot harder than just starting fresh ?
How do you mean ?
Why didn 't you just build a new house ?
Well , it 's ...
It 's his home .
Oh ...
You really love him .
Can I ask you a question ?
Why don 't you want kids ?
Excuse me ?
( CHUCKLES )
I saw how you reacted earlier .
I know what it 's like when you 're just starting out ,
and you think you have all the time in the world .
You know , you 're not going to be so young forever .
Have kids .
Then you 'll be creating something together .
That 's what keeps a marriage going .
This ... This is all just
setting .
Oh , you do want them .
Is it him ?
- I 'm gonna get back to work . - Then why did he say ...
I 'm sorry .
Was I too forward ? I do that sometimes .
Every relationship has its issues .
And when there 's a full generation between you ,
I can only imagine .
( GASPS )
Is that where he works ?
That 's private .
Oh , can 't you just give me a peek ?
He doesn 't like anyone being in there without him !
Wow . You really do love him .
God help you .
( LAUGHING )
MOTHER : Where are you going ?
- I 'm gonna take him outside . - We 're going on a hike .
A hike ?
- Me on a hike ! - Just a quick one .
Go slow .
Yeah , slow enough so my smoke doesn 't burn too quickly .
- You don 't want to come ? - No , we have laundry to do .
( MEN LAUGHING )
You 'll show me where , right ?
MAN : Which way ? HIM : Doesn 't matter .
- The boys have bonded , don 't you think ? - Mmm-hmm .
Mine 's not usually such a nature boy .
Wow . Guess you haven 't quite got to this part yet .
( SIGHS ) This is so heavy .
That 's a lot of tools .
I 'll get it .
- Which is which ? - On the left .
WOMAN : Oh , it 's full .
Oh , wait ! I 'll help you .
Oh , no . So that 's the problem .
What ?
( SOFTLY ) You 're gonna have to try harder than this .
( CHUCKLES ) I 'm sorry .
( SIGHS ) Believe me , when they get older ,
you got to keep it interesting .
He 's not that old .
How 's it going in that department ?
I don 't feel comfortable talking about that stuff .
I 'm just trying to help .
I mean , look at you .
If he 's not all over you ,
it 's either because of his age or ...
Or what ?
You know what ? Forget it .
It 's none of my business .
I think this has gone to my head .
No , it 's okay . Say what you were gonna say .
No , seriously . No , obviously he still loves you .
I 'm gonna freshen these up .
( MACHINE WHIRRING )
( TAP RUNNING )
( SCOFFS )
( TAP DRIPPING )
Hello ?
( TOILET FLUSHES )
( PLUNGER CLATTERS )
( GRUNTS )
Hey !
I told you , he doesn 't like anyone being in here without him .
It 's amazing . What is it ?
We really have to leave .
- Please ? - I just want to look at it .
You have to go .
I don 't know why you have to make such a big deal of it .
Oh , they 're back .
( MAN COUGHING )
HIM : This way . Here . WOMAN : Honey ?
- Let 's get you some water . - WOMAN : Are you all right
( MAN CONTINUES COUGHING )
Your damn smoking .
Here .
- WOMAN : You all right ? - Just started .
Come on . Let 's go get you your pills .
If I wanted a third child ...
I guess you overdid it .
Whew ! That was intense .
And you won 't believe what he just told me .
That sink 's not braced yet .
What ?
Hey , wait .
Something happened ?
What ?
What is it ? What ?
He has one of those pictures of you in his luggage .
What were you doing in their luggage ?
That 's not the point .
He didn 't just stumble on us .
- He 's a crazy fan . - I know .
Excuse me ?
That 's what he told me on our walk .
He 's dying .
( SIGHS ) Oh .
That 's why he came here .
He wanted to meet me before he 's gone .
Well , why didn 't he tell us that ?
- Why lie ? - I don 't know . I don 't know .
He 's a proud man .
I admire that .
( LOUD CRASH )
WOMAN : Oh !
HIM : What have you done ? MAN : I 'm so sorry .
We 're both sorry . I was telling her this story and ...
It just ... It just fell out of my hand .
- We 'll search and find you another one . - WOMAN : We can pay for it .
HIM : Quiet !
( GASPS )
I 'm sorry I screamed . I just need a moment .
It was an accident .
I think it 's best if you leave .
We said we were sorry .
- Honey , don 't antagonize her . - Well , what more do you want ?
Just ... It 'll be okay .
( SIGHS )
( GASPS )
Please .
- Please ! - ( GASPS )
( WOMAN MOANING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( SIGHS )
( GASPS )
( CLATTERS )
( MACHINE WHIRRING )
( BUZZES AND STOPS )
( HAMMERING )
What are you doing ?
They will never get in here again .
( CONTINUES HAMMERING )
Well , don 't worry . I 'm kicking them out .
Yeah . And where will they go ?
Need something ?
- Are you ready ? - What do you mean ?
( MAN COUGHING )
We want you out .
We ? Or you ?
- I 've tried very hard ... - Yeah , well , look ,
I have to check on my husband .
( DOOR OPENS )
YOUNGER BROTHER : Hello ? Hello !
Where is everybody ?
Oh , hey .
Hey , who are you ?
Who are you ? What are you doing here ?
What are any of us doing here , right ?
Where 's my mother ?
Uh , she 's ... Wait here .
Hey , nice view .
( DOOR OPENS )
- Did you invite your son ? - What are you doing here ?
Mum , I tried calling , but I couldn 't get through .
WOMAN : What 's wrong ?
He came to the house and found the will .
- What ? - Yeah , he 's out of control .
I 'm sorry , but whatever this is ,
- you 'll have to finish this ... - OLDEST SON : Dad !
- He 's here ? - What ? Oh , no .
- Who 's that ? - OLDEST SON : Dad ! Dad !
Yeah , ran straight to Mummy .
You followed me . What 's wrong with you ?
- WOMAN : You shouldn 't be here . - Where 's Dad ? Where is he ?
Who is she ? Who are you ? Who are you ?
- He doesn 't want to see you . - That 's not true . Is he here ?
- Dad ! - MAN : Boys ?
Boys , why are you here ?
What is this ? Do you know what you 've signed ?
- Of course I do ! - WOMAN : Go lie back down .
You said that you told him .
No , honey , I didn 't say that . I was going to .
You wanted this ? How could you ?
MAN : It 's for a good reason , son .
Let me explain to him .
- I 'll talk to him . - No , I 'll talk to him .
You 're right . I should have told you myself .
And I 'm sorry . I promise you that I was thinking about you .
Stop it ! About what 's best for all of us .
Just listen to Dad !
It 's a trust . You have to make a decision
as a group before anything can be spent .
It won 't work . I have to get permission
from them every time I take a piss ?
It will force you to get along .
That 's the most important thing .
She will side with him every time .
You 're not even listening to me !
WOMAN : No , no ! I just want to support both of you .
OLDEST SON : Support me ?
You just want to tell me what I can and can 't do .
WOMAN : That is not fair !
OLDEST SON : You never believe in me or anything I try to do .
Don 't do this , Dad . They hate me !
MAN : They don 't hate you . WOMAN : We love you .
You 're my son .
OLDEST SON : Well , then treat me like one !
The sons are here .
They just barged in . I couldn 't stop them .
I know .
YOUNGER BROTHER : Yeah , if you don 't waste it all .
OLDEST SON : Shut up ! YOUNGER BROTHER : Here we go again .
Losing his temper when he doesn 't get his way .
Let 's discuss this outside . Our hosts are here .
No ! I want to talk about it now .
- I want to talk about it now , Dad . - YOUNGER BROTHER : Shut up !
If you need money , I 'll give you money .
I don 't want your chump change !
- Don 't touch me ! - ( SHRIEKS )
Calm down . Calm down .
( PANTING )
You 're the poet ? The great writer ?
You don 't know anything .
They lied to me , they 're robbing me .
I don 't know their story , but will you calm down ?
Will you ?
Thank you .
You can sit in there .
Let 's go sit down and discuss this .
No ! Mum , Dad 's dying ,
and all he cares about is his damn money !
- No ! Stop it ! - Boys ! Boys , stop it ! ( GROANS )
Look at Dad ! Look what you did !
( SHRIEKS )
( GRUNTING )
Stop !
WOMAN : Boys ! Stop it !
Stop ! Please !
HIM : Can you breathe ? Breathe .
( SPITS )
No !
( SCREAMS )
- Come here ! - MOTHER : Wait ! Stop !
- YOUNGER BROTHER : What 's wrong with you ? - Stop it !
No ! Stop !
No !
- ( GRUNTS ) - ( SHRIEKS )
No ! No !
OLDEST SON : Get off !
Get up .
Get up ! Get up !
Stop faking . Get up .
Get up . Look at me !
( PANTING )
No , look . It 's not my fault .
It 's not my fault . They never really loved me .
They always loved him more . They were leaving me behind .
Just tell me you understand .
Tell me you understand !
( SOBBING )
You have to understand .
HIM : What have you done to your brother ?
WOMAN : My baby . My baby .
What did you do ?
( SOBBING ) What did you do ?
You did this .
Wake up ! Do something ! Help him !
- Towels . Towels . - Okay .
( DOOR OPENS )
- HIM : Easy now . - Father ...
- The doctor . Go get him . - Okay .
- Come quick ! - What ?
- What 's happening ? - He 's bleeding .
- It 's bad ! It 's really bad . - He 's not waking up . He 's not waking up .
WOMAN : Careful . Careful ! Don 't drop him .
I 'll call you from the hospital .
- MAN : Keep his head up . - No ! No , please stay with me .
Please , we need him .
Lock the doors . I 'll be back as soon as I can .
Please don 't leave me ! Please don 't leave me !
( PANTING )
( BUZZING )
( RUMBLING )
( PULSATING )
( GASPS SOFTLY )
( WATER TRICKLING )
( GASPS )
( GRUNTS )
( CROAKS )
( GASPS )
( GLASS BREAKS )
( GLASS CRUNCHES )
- Hey . - ( GASPS )
They left you all alone ?
You do understand .
( GASPING )
( GROANS )
Good luck .
( DOOR CLOSES )
( LINE RINGING )
ORACLE : 911 . What 's your emergency ?
- What 's your emergency ? - ( GASPS )
You all right ?
( SOBS ) He was here !
I know . I know . The police brought me home .
They 'll find him . Don 't worry .
- Did he hurt you ? - No .
- No ? - No .
Okay .
Okay , sit .
Let me get you some water .
Here .
It 's okay .
It 's all right .
What happened at the hospital ?
I was holding the boy 's hand when he died .
Oh , that 's awful .
Are you all right ?
I 'm exhausted .
I need a hot shower .
Will you come ?
Yeah .
What is it ?
- I 'll be up in a minute . - You sure ?
Yeah .
( SNORING )
( FOOTSTEPS )
( DOOR OPENS )
In here ?
WOMAN : Yeah , straight ahead in the kitchen .
They came back quick .
What are they doing here ?
They had nowhere to go ,
so I told them it would be all right to invite some friends and family .
I 'll go deal with them .
HIM : I 'm so sorry . WOMAN : Thank you .
HIM : I 'm so sorry for your loss .
HIM : You 're all so welcome here .
Please make yourselves at home .
I 'm so sorry .
Shall we have a toast ?
MOURNER : Yes , let 's .
MOURNER 2 : Make sure everyone has one .
( WHISPERS ) Would you say something ?
He so respects you .
- HIM : Of course . - Thank you .
Everyone .
Well , how can one begin to understand your pain ?
The sacrifice of the parent .
CUPBEARER : Here you go .
HIM : All those years of worry .
Years in days , days in hours , hours in seconds .
But in each second ,
an infinite amount of love .
And now ,
suddenly ,
it seems there is nothing to love .
Just a vast and silent darkness .
( WOMAN SOBBING )
HIM : But fear not .
From inside it , there 's a voice crying out to be heard ...
( WOMAN SOBBING )
... loud and strong .
Just listen .
Oh , God .
( ALL SOBBING )
Do you hear that ?
Do you hear that ? That is the sound of life .
That is the sound of humanity .
That is your son 's voice .
His cry of love .
His love for you .
- Thank you . - My pleasure .
CUPBEARER : Hear , hear !
ALL : Hear , hear !
( GLASSES CLINK )
WOMAN : Thank you all for coming here and being with us tonight .
My husband and I are so touched .
We lost our baby today .
( DOORBELL RINGS )
WOMAN : I just ...
I can 't believe that just a few hours ago ,
he was standing there , and I was holding him in my arms .
He was so full of life .
He always was .
- Hello . - Thank you .
- Where should I put this ? - FRIEND : Maybe in here .
( WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY )
WOMAN : Now he 'll never wander again .
I 'll never hold him again like I did today .
He 'll never laugh again .
I just want to thank you all for being here .
It means so much . I don 't know what else to say .
I just want to thank our dear host for his hospitality
- in our time of need . - Of course .
So , please ,
I 'd like to drink to your kindness .
CONSOLER : Excuse me .
WOMAN : Sweetheart , you don 't have to do this .
No , I want to .
I loved my son .
I loved him .
( SOBS )
I can 't believe this .
But I shouldn 't be eulogize him .
He 'd say ...
( SIGHS )
( SOBBING ) I 'm sorry ...
I 'm sorry . I can 't .
Would someone please ...
Would you say something ?
I ...
For your child .
For both your children . Come .
Let 's not forget the one still in the wilderness .
( DOOR OPENS )
Wherever he goes , wherever he is ...
Welcome . Please join us .
I 'm just gonna put this in the kitchen .
HIM : Yes , through there .
May he find kindness , compassion ...
- CONSOLER : I 'll wait here . - I 'll be right back .
FOOL : Hey , how you doing ?
CONSOLER : I 'm good , considering .
Um , excuse me . Could you get down from there ?
That sink 's not braced yet .
Oh , I 'm sorry .
( GLASS CRUNCHING )
Oh , there 's glass there .
That was so beautiful , no ?
It 's all right .
Can I use your phone ?
Sure . It 's in the kitchen .
No , it 's just ...
Excuse me ?
Where did you go ?
I was just in the ...
I 'm really sorry , again .
I know you are .
- I can 't imagine ... - No .
You can 't imagine what it feels like if you don 't have a child .
You give , and you give , and you give , and ...
It 's just never enough .
- I understand . - Do you ?
Why don 't you at least put on something decent ?
( INDISTINCT CHATTERING )
( CUPBEARER LAUGHS )
Hey !
You can 't be in here .
- I 'm sorry ? - You need to leave .
- We 'll just be a minute . - This is our room !
( CHUCKLES )
CUPBEARER : It 's okay .
It 's your room .
Come on . Let 's find another spot .
( GROANS )
( GASPING )
Oh .
Excuse me .
Just exploring .
( PANTING )
( SIGHS )
( SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY )
Excuse me .
Could you please go downstairs ?
- This way ? - Yes .
IDLER : Sure .
What is ...
What are you doing ?
Oh , it 's no big deal .
I worked my way through college doing this .
But why are you painting my house ?
Well , he 's been so kind to everyone ,
it 's the least we could do .
Stop !
Both of you . Stop !
No problem .
( INDISTINCT CHATTERING )
HIM : Yes , of course . What 's mine is yours .
There you are ! My goddess . Come here .
Please , make some room for her .
You 've got to hear these stories .
All these people !
I know . They 're just letting off steam .
They 're painting our house !
HIM : Oh !
- HIM : You all right ? - ( LAUGHING )
MOURNER : I told you to stop drinking .
I got it .
MOURNER 2 : Napkins ! MOURNER 1 : Yeah , I got some .
MOURNER 2 : Are you all right ?
HIM : The chair might not be all right .
FOOL : After spending a few days with my mother ...
Please ! Get down from there .
Sorry .
Excuse me .
( SIGHS )
- FOOL : What 's her problem ? - I don 't know .
Hey , we haven 't met .
I 've known this family for years . And you ?
This is my house .
( CHUCKLES )
Well , it 's a beautiful home . You want to take a walk ?
- What ? - A walk . With me .
No . No .
Please !
- Take my number . - No , I don 't want your number .
Why would you say that ? You don 't even know me .
- Let go of me ! - Why ?
Because I don 't know you .
- Get down from there . - From where ?
You don 't know what I could do for you .
I don 't want anything from you .
Sassy .
Leave me alone .
You know what ? Get out of my face .
You 're an arrogant cunt .
This sink . There 's nothing wrong with it .
It 's really okay .
No , stop doing that . Don 't do that . Stop !
Stop doing that ! Stop , stop !
( PEOPLE SCREAMING )
Get out ! Get out , all of you !
What happened ?
They won 't listen !
It 's all right . We 'll fix it . It can be fixed .
- WOMAN : We 're being punished . - Please , don 't go . Don 't go .
- We 'll turn it off . - It 's been an honor .
We will never forget all you 've done for us .
HIM : But where will you go ?
- ( DOOR CLOSES ) - ( CHATTERING STOPS )
( WATER TRICKLING )
( CUTLERY CLATTERING )
They 're gone .
Come . Let 's go to bed . You don 't need to do that .
Do what ?
Clean up their mess ?
We did a good thing .
They needed a place to celebrate life .
They needed tonight .
What about what I needed ?
A boy died here today . I mopped up his blood .
- And you abandoned me . - No , no , I didn 't abandon you .
They just lost a son . They lost , well , two sons !
I was helping them . This is not about us . It 's about them .
No ! It 's not about them . It 's about you .
It 's always about you and your work .
You think that 's gonna help you write ?
Nothing does !
I rebuilt this entire house , wall to wall .
You haven 't written a word !
I know ! I know ! I 'm sorry ! I can 't ... I can 't write !
I can 't think !
All I 'm trying to do is bring life into this house !
Open the door to new people , new ideas .
You think you can 't breathe ?
I 'm the one who 's suffocating here
while you pretend that nothing is wrong !
" Everything will be all right . Everything will be good .
" You 'll be fine . " You know what ?
Life doesn 't always work out the way you want it to .
You 're right .
Mine certainly didn 't .
Excuse me ?
You talk about wanting kids , but you can 't even fuck me .
- Come here . Come here ! - No ! No !
( GRUNTING )
( PANTING )
I 'm pregnant .
Hmm ?
We 're gonna have a baby .
( CHUCKLES )
I 'm serious .
How could you know ?
Because I know .
I 'm pregnant .
( SOFTLY ) A baby ...
- Are you happy ? - Happy ?
That 's the most beautiful gift .
What ?
Pen , pen , pen .
What are you doing ?
I 'm writing .
- What ? - Writing .
Last night , those people .
Their pain . Their love behind the pain . And then ...
You .
Us .
And now that .
Life .
It 's coming to me . It 's ...
I know what to say . I have to find the words . That 's all .
Amazing .
Well , I won 't ...
I don 't want to interrupt .
I 'll just get started on the apocalypse .
Hey .
I love you .
( TOILET FLUSHES )
( GROANS )
( GASPS )
It moved ! It moved !
What is it ?
Is that it ?
I finished it .
May I ?
( WIND WHOOSHING )
It 's beautiful .
Really ?
Why are you crying ?
It 's just a lot .
You think it 's good ?
It 's perfect .
But then what 's going on ?
Am I going to lose you ?
Never .
( PHONE RINGING )
Hello ?
Hi .
Yes ?
Really ?
- Really . - Who is that ?
One moment . Give me a second . They loved it .
Who did ?
What ? Yeah , I 'll be here , standing by .
Are you there ? Hello ?
- Who was that ? - My publisher .
- She 's read it ? - Yes . Of course . Why ?
( PHONE RINGING )
Yes .
Hi , again .
Press ? Uh , well , you know how I feel about it .
I 'd rather not . But if you think it 's a must .
I 'll be here , waiting .
( GROANS )
HIM : Wow , amazing !
Well , we 're celebrating .
One day , every copy sold .
You 're so beautiful .
Make yourself comfortable . I 'll go get everything .
Looks delicious .
- Let me help you . - No , sit .
No , I 'm helping .
( CHUCKLES ) Okay .
Will you bring the bread in ?
( CHUCKLES ) All right .
( CREAKING )
( GASPS )
ZEALOT : No . Wait , please . Can I see him ?
( LAUGHING )
( INDISTINCT CHATTER )
ZEALOT : Excuse me , I have a question .
What are you doing ?
- Who are they ? - I don 't know .
Please . Wait .
What do they want ?
I don 't know . They 've come here to see me .
FAN : Please ! I just want to get a photo with him .
ZEALOT : He 'll be back in a moment .
Just keep everything warm . I 'll be right in .
You had a question .
- Yeah . - What is it ?
ZEALOT : As I was saying , we 've all travelled a great distance ,
and I feel that , uh ...
Well , these words ,
I feel like they were written for me .
HIM : Of course they were .
( INDISTINCT CHATTERING )
( GASPING )
( CROWD CHATTERING )
( CROWD CLAMORING )
( CAMERA CLICKING )
My goddess ! Come here .
Come .
- No , stay away from me ! - Please leave her . Thank you .
They love it . They understand all of it .
But it affects everyone in a different way .
It is remarkable . Come . They want to meet you .
No , I don 't want to . I don 't want to . Come inside .
But they 've come from so far .
Look at me !
I 'm about to have our baby .
Why is that not enough for you ?
Of course it 's enough .
I 'm not going anywhere . I 'm here , with you .
I want to be alone with you .
I 'm with you .
Give me a second .
( CROWD CLAMORING )
( FAN SHRIEKS )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( CROWD CHEERING )
SUPPLICANT : Come , come , come . Quick , quick .
Just hang in there . Hold it in .
MOTHER : Hey !
I 'm sure there 's a bathroom really close .
- Hold it in . - Excuse me .
Do you know where the bathroom is ?
- You need to leave . - Where should I go ?
I don 't know , but you can 't be in here .
But my son , he , um ...
MOTHER : Oh ...
Okay . Come with me .
Thank you so much . I 'll come back and clean up .
Did you open this ?
SUPPLICANT : Okay , here we go . Just a little bit longer .
It 's okay . We 'll get you dried off .
After you 've finished , I really need you to go back outside .
( URINATING )
What are you doing ?
How about a little privacy ?
Please ?
MOTHER : Sir !
I 've been waiting a long time . Excuse me .
- Hey , wait your turn , lady . - MOTHER : No !
How did you get in here ?
Could you get the two of us , please ?
- No , I got it . I got it . - Thanks .
- Okay , get down on the floor . - It 's beautiful .
Don 't touch that !
- ( CAMERA CLICKS ) - AESTHETE : It 's so organic .
WOMAN IN LINE : Hey , stop pushing !
All of you need to go outside .
Hey ! Sir !
I 'm just gonna lie down for a bit . I don 't feel so good .
- No , no , you cannot lie down here . - Why ? You staying in here ?
I live here . This is my house .
( LAUGHS ) " My house " ? " My house " ?
The poet says it 's everyone 's house !
( DOOR OPENS )
Food and drink , my friends .
ZEALOT : I believe it 's , um , yes , right back here .
Hey !
ZEALOT : Oh , this is nice . We 've got vegetables ...
MOTHER : Stop ! All of you .
ZEALOT : Check the cabinets . And the fridge !
What are you doing ?
Oh , beautiful !
No ! No ! That 's not for you .
ZEALOT : He said to share .
But it 's not yours !
They 're hungry and thirsty . Here you go .
Now , take the fruit and the cheese and the pickles .
Excuse me . Watch your backs .
You can put that over there . And that goes over there . Thank you .
DISCIPLE 1 : Looks great , let 's share it .
DISCIPLE 2 : I 'll slice this up .
DISCIPLE 3 : You can sit here , sir .
DISCIPLE 1 : There 'll be no photos , just autographs !
Your writing is so beautiful .
What is this ? What are you doing ?
I 'm showing them my appreciation .
- Hey ! - HERALD : Oh , hi !
Oh ! My genius .
( LAUGHS )
Look at you .
- The second printing is here . - Great .
Yes . I wish you would 've told me about this turnout .
- Have you met my ... - There she is .
Oh ...
The inspiration .
All right , I have to be honest .
I was a little worried about him being holed up here with you .
I was nervous you 'd never write again .
HIM : Of course not .
But whatever you did , it was worth it .
And look at you . You 're ready to pop !
How are you feeling ? Hot ?
It 's hot in here . Is it me ? It 's broiling .
ABETTOR : I 've got it right here .
Oh , yes . Will you excuse me ?
Let me see . Take it out !
Oh , yes . That 's exactly what I wanted .
- Um , the original , where is it ? - It 's right there by the desk .
- ZEALOT : I 've got it ! - Excuse me .
- I 've got it . - I 'll take that , thank you .
- Oh . No , it 's okay . - No , don 't touch it !
- No , it 's fine . - Don 't touch it !
- No ! Get your hands off it ! - HIM : What happened ?
Wait , wait ! Easy , easy , easy .
HERALD : I 'm trying to put it in this frame .
HIM : Okay , I 'll do it . It 's all good .
Hey !
Stop ! Give that back . Give it back .
No , I have to have something of his ! No !
( BOTH GRUNTING )
It 's mine !
You did it ! Now I got to find something else !
Get out ! All of you !
Stop ! This doesn 't belong to you !
( LINE RINGING )
ORACLE : 911 . What 's your emergency ?
Can you help me ?
What is your emergency , ma 'am ?
They 're stealing everything !
Thank you .
I was using that !
That 's all right . Share , like the poet said .
Yeah , share .
That 's not right .
( SOBBING )
Look , he marked you . He marked you .
- Me , too . Please . - Okay .
- Oh , thank you . - Stop !
Stop ! Stop touching him !
They 're ruining everything .
Those are just things .
They can be replaced . Don 't worry .
- Forgive me . Just a few shots . - HIM : Of course .
- Here we go . - No !
Look right in the lens , make sure you 're getting him .
No , no , no , no , don 't go !
CHRONICLER : Please , just one more !
( SCREAMS )
( METALS CLANGING )
( CROWD CLAMORING )
( RUMBLING )
( PULSATING )
( GASPS )
MALE HELPER : You 're welcome to pin your thanks on the door .
ZEALOT : His words are yours .
Gracias .
MALE HELPER : Watch your step going down .
Next , please . Step forward .
ZEALOT : His words are yours .
ZEALOT : If you please , pin your thoughts on the wall .
MALE HELPER : Step forward .
- ZEALOT : His words are yours . - Thank you .
MALE HELPER : Next .
( CROWD CLAMORING )
( DANCE MUSIC PLAYING )
( GRUNTING )
( CHEERING )
There you are !
Where have you been hiding ?
Why are you doing this ?
Proof we were here .
- Get off of me ! - FEMALE FAN : What the hell !
COPPERSMITH : I 'll kill you !
- Watch your back . - Heads up . Coming through .
No ! Don 't .
( YELLING )
( GASPS )
( SCREAMING )
- Hey ! - ( GRUNTS ) No ! Let go !
No , you can 't leave ! He loves you !
I got it . Where are you going ? Don 't . Don 't go .
You don 't want me here .
Come here . Look here .
- I 'm here . - I can 't .
Listen , I have to tell you something .
( GROANS AND GASPS )
HIM : What ?
The baby ? The baby ?
- Come here . Come , come . - DISCIPLE : Lock the back door !
We need space ! We need space !
Hold on here . I 'll be right back .
Back ! Back ! Give us some room !
( SIRENS WAILING )
( GLASS SHATTERS )
OFFICER : Police ! Get on the ground !
Help me . Help me . No !
Against the wall !
Please don 't ! My baby ! Please don 't !
Get off her ! Get off !
Back off !
( SCREAMS )
I call dibs !
( SOBBING )
( GASPING )
( INDISTINCT SHOUTING )
( GUNSHOTS )
( CROWD SCREAMING )
Ah !
( GIRL SCREAMING )
Where you going , huh ? Get inside !
GIRLS : Somebody help us , please !
( SCREAMS IN PAIN )
Shut up !
- How 's Angel ? - Tainted .
WHOREMONGER : Check the goyim .
- Move ! - ( GROANS )
( SCREAMS )
( SHOUTING SLOGANS )
- I didn 't do anything ! - REVOLUTIONARY : Get in there !
- Quiet ! - Keep your mouths shut .
( MUFFLED SCREAM )
( SHRIEKS )
HERALD : The inspiration !
Where have you been hiding ?
Finish her .
REVOLUTIONARY : On your knees !
HERALD : All right , six more .
( EXPLOSION )
( GROANING )
OFFICER ON PA : Disperse !
( SCREAMS )
Freeze !
Oh , no . Come on .
( GUNS FIRING )
Are you hurt ?
The baby ...
( MOTHER SCREAMS )
Medic !
( SCREAMS AND GASPS )
FLEEING MAN : This way .
Go , hurry . Just go !
( GRUNTING )
( GROANS )
My darling ! It 's me ! It 's me .
What 's happening ?
I don 't know . I have to take you somewhere safe .
- There . - No , no , no .
- Out ! - It 's too dangerous .
Come with me . Quietly .
( PEOPLE COUGHING )
This way .
- The door ! - HIM : No , no , it 's this way .
It 's him ! It 's the poet !
He hasn 't forsaken us after all !
We need to hurry . Stay close .
We need money ! We need to eat ! Please !
Get back ! Get back ! Please , no , I can 't ! I can 't !
I 'm sorry . I 'm sorry . I can 't !
( GROANS )
I will not forget you .
ZEALOT : Poet , over here ! Come on !
Up here ! Up here !
HIM : Up there ! Up there .
They will protect us .
Come . I 've got you .
HIM : Grab the hand .
Get back ! Get back ! I will return !
Hold them back !
Sit here . Rest .
- I 'm a doctor ! - A doctor ? Please help her .
Help her , please . Here . I 'll be right back .
Oh , that 's good .
Don 't leave us !
Get off !
HEALER : Look at me . Listen to my voice .
( GRUNTS AND SCREAMS )
The baby 's almost here .
( PANTING )
HEALER : Just a little bit further . You can do this .
Push .
Just push .
- No . - Yes , yes !
You have to push . Push !
Push . You 're almost there . Yes !
Do it again .
Yes , you 're doing very good .
- I can feel the head . - Please move . I 've got her .
- ZEALOT : Wait ! I can help . - I 'm delivering my baby !
- ZEALOT : Let me help ! - Shut the door !
Shut it !
We 're safe .
It 's okay . Our baby 's coming .
Our baby 's coming . Our baby 's coming .
Our baby 's coming .
( SCREAMS )
( RUMBLING )
Okay .
It 's almost here .
( CONTINUES SCREAMING )
It 's here . It 's coming . It 's coming !
HIM : It 's a boy .
( GASPS )
It 's a boy .
It 's a boy , look .
- It 's a boy . - ( COOING )
( BOTH LAUGH )
Cover him .
( CRYING )
( CLAMORING STOPS )
What 's happening ?
Why are they so quiet ?
( WHISPERS ) I don 't know .
Don 't !
Don 't do that .
It 's okay .
- Shut the door . - ( DOOR CLOSES )
Seal it !
They brought us gifts .
- Here . - What are they doing ?
They 're just waiting .
Waiting for what ?
I don 't know .
Make them go .
Please .
Please make them .
- Please . - Okay , okay .
( DOOR CLOSES )
- ( BABY CRYING ) - ( SHUSHING )
More gifts . Look . Look .
For you . Clean clothes .
Are they leaving ?
What ?
No , they ... They just want to see him .
No .
Make them go .
I can 't . I can 't .
Yes , you can ! They adore you . They would listen to you .
- Why won 't you ? - I don 't want them to go !
( BABY COOING )
He 's beautiful .
- Let me hold him . - No .
Okay , let me hold him .
- Let me hold my baby . - No .
- Let me hold him . - No .
- I 'm his father ! - I 'm his mother !
( SIGHS )
( DEEP EXHALE )
( BABY COOING )
- Here , let me ... - No !
Please ?
Please make them go .
( CROWD CHEERING )
No . No . No .
No !
Give me back my baby !
Where is he ?
( CROWD EXCLAIMING )
( BABY CRYING )
Wait ! Stop !
No ! That 's my baby !
No ! No ! Give me back ...
WORSHIPPER 1 : Hallelujah ! WORSHIPPER 2 : Praise be !
WORSHIPPER 3 : Hallelujah !
- You 're gonna hurt him ! - ( BABY WAILING )
Please ! Please ! Please !
You 're gonna hurt him !
You 're hurting him ! You 're hurting him !
( CRACKS )
- ( BABY STOPS CRYING ) - ( GASPS )
Where is he ?
- Where 's my baby ? - He 's not dead .
- What ? Where is he ? - A voice
still cries out to be heard , loud and strong .
- Listen . - What ?
( ALL SOBBING )
Do you hear that ?
( SOBS ) No ! No !
( GASPS )
( SCREAMING )
ZEALOT : Do you hear that ?
- That 's the sound of life . - ( PEOPLE CHOMPING )
The sound of humanity !
His cry of love !
His love for you !
( SCREAMS )
Get off ! Get off !
You killed him !
- Die , cunt ! - Dirty whore !
Slut ! Bitch !
Fat pig !
You bitch !
Take that , tramp !
- Cunt ! - Kill the pig !
HIM : Please !
Please stop ! Stop , please !
Go away . Leave her alone . What are you doing ?
Look what they 've done to you .
What are you doing ? What are you doing ?
( SOBS ) They killed my baby !
You killed him .
I 'm so sorry . I 'm so sorry .
They just want to see him . They just want to touch him ,
and then they ...
It was ...
It 's horrible . I 'm sorry . I 'm so sorry .
But we can 't ...
We can 't let him die for nothing . We can 't .
Maybe what happened could change everything .
Everyone .
- What are you talking about ? - We ...
You and I , we have to find a way to forgive them .
They butchered our son !
I know . I know .
You 're insane .
- Listen to me . - You 're insane .
Well , listen to them . They are so sorry .
They are truly sorry .
Listen . Have faith in me . Please . Please .
We need to forgive them . We need to forgive them !
Please . Please ! We have to !
( RUMBLING )
( PULSATING WEAKLY )
( PULSATING STOPS )
No !
Murderers !
Murderer !
It 's time to get the fuck out of my house !
( CROWD GASPING )
HIM : No , no . No , no , no !
No ! Please ! Don 't leave !
Please ! I beg you !
Don 't run off ! We will rebuild !
( GRUNTS )
Don 't ! Don 't leave me alone !
( CROWD CLAMORING )
( GROANS )
ZEALOT : This way ! She went down here !
Stop ! Stop ! Wait . Wait .
( GRUNTS )
Don 't ! Don 't ! Don 't !
Please don 't .
I love you .
You never loved me .
You just loved how much I loved you .
I gave you everything !
You gave it all away .
No . No . No .
No , no , no , no !
( SCREAMING )
( SOFT GROANING )
What are you ?
Me ?
I am I.
You ?
You were home .
Where are you taking me ?
The beginning .
( GROANS )
Is that it ?
It won 't hurt much longer .
What hurts me the most is that I wasn 't enough .
It 's not your fault .
Nothing is ever enough .
I couldn 't create if it was .
And I have to . That 's what I do .
That 's what I am .
Now I must try it all again .
No .
Just let me go .
I need one last thing .
I have nothing left to give .
Your love .
It 's still there , isn 't it ?
Go ahead .
Take it .
( EXHALES )
( MOTHER GASPING )
( EXHALES DEEPLY )
( HIM GRUNTS )
( BLOWS )
( LAUGHING )
Baby ?
( SOFT MUSIC PLAYING )